For all my fellow autistics, this video might clarify why many of us are not liked in the workplace, in our friendships, or relationships. I'll come back after.
Autistic professionals can be among the most disliked and simultaneously misunderstood people in the workplace. But here's the thing.
It has a lot to do with processing styles, bottom-up versus top-down. And if you're autistic, you're more likely to be that one.
If you're a bottom-up processor, you might notice small errors like typos or minor inaccuracies, even if others don't.
Prefer having all the details before forming a conclusion.
Get slowed down if information feels incomplete or vague.
Focus on how something is said or done, not just the overall message.
Correct others when details are off because it feels important to the integrity of the information.
And excel at finding unexpected problems before they become bigger issues.
If you're a top-down processor, you might form a big-picture understanding, even with limited information.
Fill in gaps with assumptions, context, or prior knowledge.
Value efficiency and be able to overlook small errors.
Find detailed explanations unnecessary.
Be able to summarize the key points rather than focusing on details.
And excel at keeping projects on schedule, delegating, and aligning tasks with goals.
Like and share so that we can further these bridges of understanding.
They're like, oh my god, this person is so annoying.
So if you've been following me, you notice that this is how I process everything, okay?
This is how I process the world.
This is how I process television shows.
And if you've worked with me, you know full well that this is how I process in a workspace,
both as a leader or as somebody who is hired.
And so often, this has had me labeled by co-workers, by employees, by partners, by friends as negative, pessimistic, a dark cloud.
When really, in actuality, it's just, oh, I'm looking at something differently.
And I would always be explaining like, no, I'm not trying to be negative or pessimistic.
I'm just trying to get us on the right track from Jump Street so that we don't have to wrangle us back.
And thank you to executive producer, Jesse Collins, who was the first person I ever worked with that actually noticed this about me before I even noticed this about me.
And then communicated it to everybody so that they would understand how I work so that we could all work really well and efficiently together.
Man, it's such a gift to be able to see your brain processed so that you can understand how you process so you can stop hating yourself, even though the world constantly is telling you to do so.
Thank you, Kaylin.
Support a real one.